The final point I want to make about this is a sobering one,
which is about not getting caught up in the hype
of agentic coding.
Now look, generally I am a huge fan, very passionate
about the impact that LLMs can make to software development,
but there is certainly some hype out there
that is unwarranted.
There are some tasks for sure where using LLMs
can make it an order of magnitude faster
to deliver.
If you're building a boilerplate React frontend, which is going to evolve a lot of
componentry and you've got a very good sense of what you want the UI to look like, an
LLM can do that in a matter of minutes when it would take a great frontend person, maybe
a day and it would take me several weeks.
So certainly for me, order of magnitude difference.
But there are some tasks where LLMs are only incrementally faster than just doing it yourself.
And indeed, I've had experiences where I feel like it has actually slowed me down
because I had to go in and rewrite something where there was a mistake, a very subtle mistake that I wasn't expecting. Netnet, there is no question that LLMs are a huge value add and
that I'm able to achieve a lot more as a result of using them. How much more depends critically
on the project. More highly innovative projects with larger code bases and the improvement becomes
more incremental. Starting out with something completely new where it's a complete Greenfields project, and where I'm
working on something where there's plenty of boilerplate code in there, like, as I say,
a sort of boilerplate React frontend. That's the kind of thing where LLMs can change the game.
Days turn into minutes. It can be that radical. So there are both extremes there as in aggregate for me, it is a multiplier but it's not a 10X and that's
something which I think we all have to have that kind of very reasonable grounded opinion and be
sure to set the record straight if people, there's people that are that are too caught up in the hype
and there are also now there's a sort of movement of people who are anti-AI, perhaps because they've got frustrated by the hype
and they've had some negative experiences.
So it's encumbered on us to do the work, to learn about these tools, to use them and
then to set the record straight.
Both the pros and the cons be able to explain where they are highly beneficial and where
they still have some room to grow.
And as the final topic for today, I have lots of courses which go into tons of detail about
the different LLMs out there, but it's worth having a quick mention of it because this
is such an important part of what we're going to be doing.
There's a website called artificialanalysis.ai, and I have that right up here to show you.
And this is one, this is one I know that people don't use bookmarks anymore if I say
you should add this to your bookmarks.
I said like I'm but I still use Facebook.
But you should add this to your bookmarks.
Only have one bookmark.
It should be artificialanalysis.ai.
Here it is.
And yeah, this is a website that allows you to compare the different models.
And when you bring up artificialanalysis.ai, you're going to see something different to
me because models change so fast.
And you're going to be lucky that you're going to see,
you're going to have even better experiences than me. But what you find on this page is various
different ways to compare the different LLMs out there in terms of intelligence and speed and price
dimensioned in all sorts of different ways. And we'll look at some of them now. So this is the
So this is the intelligence index, which is the single encompassing score from these people as official analysis on how smart a model is.
And what you'll see is that in top position are the models that I mentioned, they're all
sort of around November 2025, which was a point of inflection when suddenly these agentic,
these coding agents really had a step change in terms of how much you can trust them.
And there are still some naysayers out there who are still burnt, have scar tissue,
from how the models used to be before November 2025.
And you have to sort of encourage them to come back and give it another try,
because so much has changed since then.
And here we have, like we used yesterday, GPT 5.2 from OpenAI.
That is considered at least by this index
to be the smartest model.
Claude Opus 4.5 comes next.
It is my model of choice,
but that's partly because I use it within Claude code.
And that whole environment is so geared
towards productive coding. And then GPT 5.2 codex is just a variant of GPT 5.2
that's more designed for coding. And Gemini 3 Pro is of course Google's latest strongest
model at least as of now. And that also scores quite well. And then before that, you see where the models used to be and you can see it made a big jump
suddenly in in in around
November of last year and I would encourage you to spend time on this site
I'm not going to go through it now, but you'll see so much here including this amazing chart that shows frontier model intelligence over time
It does have this slightly spooky way of appearing to be on a curve upwards in terms of intelligence.
I personally think that that's because there's been a couple of bumps. One of them came in the
last year or so with this big boost because of these new reasoning techniques. So I don't think
that curve is going to continue to steepen, but you'll be able to see you. We have to go and look
right now and see whether my prediction is right. I expect to see more improvement this year,
but not a continual sharpening slope.
So you will have better models than me
and you should see that in your outputs.
So have a look through this site.
You'll also see a number of these individual tests,
including a specific coding related test
that you'll see here to see what comes through strongest
in terms of coding and here in terms of being able to use tools
and what comes through most strongly. And you'll see here that this open source model,
GLM47 from Z.AI, the Chinese AI startup, is really, really strong there. So spend some time,
look at this and use this incredible resource, this amazing website to learn more about the
different models and the different models
and the different providers
and find out how much the world has changed
since since I look at artificial analysis to AI right here.
And with that, that wraps up day two of week one,
we've covered the foundations you've put up with me
talking more than I'll talk
and any other point in this course.
So thank you.
And tomorrow we're going to look at tools, tools, tools.
We're going to look at Cursor,
Copilot, Codex, Anti-Ggravity. It's going to be really
fun. I can't wait to show you all of that. But for now, take a moment to celebrate your
13% way through this journey. And we've got lots of great things ahead.